Vikas Singh

Chandigarh, Chandigarh - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Vikas-Singh/8644db42854c4f6a

I've 4.6 years of IT experience in Identity and Access Management with Infosys limited. It involves

troubleshooting and resolving workflow errors and provisioning user access. I perform identity

and access management activities, updating existing access and provisioning workflows, manage

operations within the IAM environment. Currently I'm working on automating the work flow of

Security Intelligence and Response Team with Phantom and Python scripting.

I'm trained in Python, Solaris administration, Java and PLSQL. I'm able to handle multiple tasks

and work as a team Member. I've excellent analytical, problem solving and programming skills.

I'm committed; goal oriented, & has zeal to learn new things & technologies.

I am graduated in Electronics and Communication Engineering in 2013 with excellent grades. I

possess good problem solving & interpersonal skills, good communication skills and team spirit.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Technology Analyst

Infosys Limited - Chandigarh, Chandigarh -

October 2013 to Present

# A. Change Management:

Installing and upgrading RT and RTIR for improved request handling with MySQL database.

## B. Python Automation:

Automating various use cases for the Security Intelligence and Response Team using Python

scripting and Phantom tool integrating it with various tools i.e. Splunk, Request Tracker for

Incident Response (RTIR), Remedy etc.

Below are the use cases details:

Use Cases Description

Proxy Blocks Enable the ability to block domains and URLs automatically on Bluecoat proxies

using a list maintained in SPLUNK

Palo Alto Blocks Enable the ability to block domains and URLs automatically on Palo Alto proxies

using a list maintained in SPLUNK

Threat Intel Email feed ingestion Take emails from an external distribution group and parse the

emails for IOCs

Email Eradication

When a Malicious email has been detected as being received in the Microsoft Exchange email

system perform eradication steps to remove the email from the email messaging platform

Email Quarantine Email addresses alerted as malicious need to be added to a quarantine list

Malware Response When malware is detected by alert or scanning initiate containment

procedures for the affected device in question Unapproved Devices

https://www.indeed.com/r/Vikas-Singh/8644db42854c4f6a?isid=rex-download&ikw=download-top&co=IN

When alerts for Unapproved Devices, equipment that is not in Organization's asset inventory, is triggered containment needs to occur for the device in question

IOC Detect and Scanning using Tanium and Fireeye HX When Indicators of Compromise, IOC, are received from various sources, threat intel feeds, exploded malware the network environment needs to be scanned for any of the indicators of compromise provided.

Clear Text Passwords detected Automatically flag users password to reset in Active Directory when an alert in SPLUNK for a clear text password detected fires

Create ticket from Splunk or MSSP Alert Develop a script that takes the details of an alert from an alert generated in SPLUNK and create or append to a ticket in the ticketing system in use

Triage and Identification Execute the triage and identification steps that are performed manually today

Information Security Analyst

Infosys Limited - Chandigarh, Chandigarh -

2013 to Present

A. Identity management

Infosys Limited -

May 2014 to December 2017

management May 2014 - Dec 2017

Following are my roles and responsibilities in the project: A. Identity management:

Tracking and processing identity creation for all the new hires along with basic access e.g.: Email,

Active Directory accounts and including mandatory security related groups. Also, making sure

access is disabled on the user's departure date and cleaning up of all the access. Reviewing

access periodically and updating it accordingly.

## B. Access management:

This involves provisioning/de-provisioning access to users across 300+ applications using various

global and in house tools like RSA security console, SAP, Identity IIQ etc. across multiple platforms

like, UNIX, Database and application front end. Making sure standard operative procedures (SOP)

are followed, validation checks are completed and appropriate approvals are gathered before access is granted.

#### C. Quality Management:

Performing quality checks on random samples of requests on daily basis and sharing QAP results with administrators.

- Monitoring and tracking the corrective actions are taken within defined timeframe.
- Doing RCA on major issues
- Developing Service Improvement Plan (SIP) and Process Improvement Plan (PIP) based on the QAP analysis  $\,$

## D. Risk Management:

Identifying risk areas through daily and periodic report E.g. Segregation of duties violation (SOD)

report, Active directory infraction report etc.

- Working with various teams to mitigate the violations.
- Assisting auditors by provide details and justification on audit samples.

#### E. Client Coordination:

Coordinating with client daily, weekly for the operations, issues and feedback with the respective reports prepared.

### EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication Engineering

GLA Institute of Technology and Management - Mathura, Uttar Pradesh

September 2009 to June 2013

SKILLS

SECURITY (5 years), INFORMATION SECURITY (5 years), ACTIVE DIRECTORY (3 years), UNIX (Less than 1 year)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Operating Systems: Windows, Solaris
- Languages: Python, Core Java, SQL, Unix
  Software: Sailpoint IIQ, Oracle IAM, Beeline, SAP, Active Directory, Phantom, Quest change

auditor, Microsoft Office Suite

• Information Security: Concepts and best practices